- Previously on "The Ark."
- We can't let anyone
know about this.
- Know about what?
- Hey, what's up?
[buzzing]
[panel chimes]
- That took you long
enough.
- [screams]
- I'm gonna move
the slab away from her!
[screams]
Guys, you have to see this.
[tense music]
- I think you need
to take me to med bay.
- What's wrong?
- [stuttering]
I can't--
- OK, OK, OK.
- You can freaking control me.
- [distorted]
Don't try that again.
[normally]
You owe me your life.
You should be thanking me.
- Thank you.
Now please,
get out of my head.
[breathing heavily]
- [chuckles]
Give me the silent treatment
all you want.
- Need a spotter?
- I'm OK.
- Good.
You don't need
any distractions.
Now leave.
- You know what?
I do need a spotter.
Just one a wee bit stronger.
[peaceful music]
♪ ♪
Oh?
- How's that for strong?
- I see what you're doing,
and I don't care.
- I admit I was wrong,
and I accept my defeat.
- You're going to have to pay
the price for doubting me.
- And what's that then?
- Mm-hmm.
♪ ♪
- [sighs] You know what?
Have your fun while you can.
♪ ♪
Because everything is gonna
change once we get to Homebase.
[tense music]
[monitors beeping]
- You're taking
a million cells?
- Oh, I'm extracting
a lot more than that.
But I only need a million cells
to grow a culture to study it.
OK. You're numbed.
Deep breath.
- [inhales deeply]
- I'm pretty sure the cure
for Gen-3 psychosis
has to do with why your GABA
receptor genes don't degrade.
You might feel a small pinch.
- [groans softly]
All done.
- Oh.
That wasn't too bad
for a needle to my spine.
- [chuckles] Technically,
it went in your brain stem.
- What's next?
How can I help?
- Well, I was--
- Captain.
We're picking up
a distress call.
It's from "Ark 16."
- Oh, go do captain stuff.
I'll do science stuff.
- You got it.
[soft dramatic music]
Set a course.
I'm on my way
to the bridge now.
[insects droning]
[WD chimes]
- Mr. Strickland?
- Alicia?
- Yes. Good news.
Your name's been cleared.
It's safe to come home.
- Oh, that's a relief.
Thank you.
- Oh, thank Mr. Avega.
He got Lati to trick
Ves into saying--
- Alicia?
You better send
a science team to my location.
- What? Why?
- I just found something
strange.
[dramatic music]
♪ ♪
[uplifting music]
[energy crackling]
- I repeat, this is
Captain St. John of "Ark 16."
We are under siege.
Please send help.
I re--
- The message is 31 hours old.
- Then we might still
be able to help.
What do we know?
- "Ark 16" was one
of the last Arks
to launch under GSA command.
- Where are they now?
- Dena-197,
listed in our database
as a colonization candidate.
- Could someone be challenging
them for the planet?
- Statistically unlikely.
- Not everyone is as open
to peace as you are, Captain.
- Maybe it's "EF1."
Avega still hasn't been
able to contact them.
- Maybe they missed the memo
that the war is over.
- Or it could also be a trap.
Drake is still
searching for you.
- The thought crossed my mind.
- We're approaching
the coordinates.
Dropping out of FTL
in three, two...
[panel beeps]
[soft suspenseful music]
♪ ♪
- Huh.
- I don't see any evidence
of a colony on the surface.
- I don't detect
other ships in orbit.
- Except "Ark 16."
- It looks undamaged.
- All the systems are
functioning.
There's life signs
for 285 people.
Yeah, I don't see any signs
of an attack.
- Hail them.
- I've been trying to,
but there's no response.
- Can we tap into
their internal cameras?
- They're offline.
- Then the only way we're
getting answers is to go over.
- We should be cautious.
Keep the boarding party small
and armed.
- Agreed.
Shuttle in ten.
Eva, you're with us.
♪ ♪
- So maybe
I should come with you?
- I need you here.
I'm taking Eva, so I need
an engineer on the ship.
- Oh.
Because for a second there,
I thought it was about
professional propriety.
- [chuckles]
♪ ♪
Um--
it wasn't, but now it is.
♪ ♪
- [sighs]
[metallic clanking]
- There's an unknown
contaminant in the air.
I'll take a sample.
- Copy that.
Helmets stay on.
♪ ♪
[panel beeping]
- Why are the bulkheads closed?
This seems off, right?
- Little bit.
Can you do a sweep
with Hendricks and Wilson?
Eva, see if you can
pull anything off
the internal feeds.
♪ ♪
[tense music]
- So
you and Ian finally decided
to go for it in real life?
- It's that obvious?
- Pretty much.
[panel chiming]
- Can I ask you a question?
How do you and Brice draw
professional boundaries?
- Boundaries?
Good thing you didn't walk
in on us earlier in the gym.
- [chuckles softly]
[panel chiming]
I'm in.
Half the bulkheads
are in lockdown.
Most of the WD signatures
I'm detecting
are behind the lockdowns.
- So they're either locked in
or keeping something out.
- Get away from me!
- Follow me.
[tense music]
♪ ♪
- Get away from me!
- Hey, stop!
What are you doing? Hey!
♪ ♪
- He slept with my wife!
- You don't even have a wife.
- [snarls]
- Wait!
- Kimi to Garnet.
You better come
to the Mess Hall.
- Come on.
[tense music]
♪ ♪
What happened?
- They all have
some sort of skin condition.
- Must be an infection
or some sort of poisoning
from the contaminant
we detected.
- But we just saw
two crew that have it.
They were alive.
- These people didn't die
from an infection.
This woman's head
is smashed in.
♪ ♪
This man was stabbed.
- I think this person
was strangled.
These people killed each other.
♪ ♪
[electricity zapping]
Stop!
You're killing him!
- My first officer mutinied.
[electricity crackling]
I can't allow that.
- What's on the back
of your hand, Captain?
♪ ♪
- Who are you?
- Captain Sharon Garnet.
We're from "Ark 1."
- You boarded
without permission.
- We were answering
your distress call.
What happened here?
- You want to take my ship?
- We're here to help you.
- Sir, you need
to step back now!
♪ ♪
[device beeps, alarm blaring]
- This is Captain
to anyone still loyal.
We have intruders.
Do not let them escape!
- Sharon?
- Back to the shuttle.
We'll figure this out
from "Ark 1."
Go. Go.
♪ ♪
Come on!
[alarm blaring]
♪ ♪
The less contact, the better.
Run!
[shouting and grunting]
♪ ♪
[Eva yelps]
- Kimi!
Come on.
Go.
Go, go, go!
Come on, Eva!
Hurry!
[crew shouting]
♪ ♪
[people thudding against door]
- Decontamination protocol.
Clear in five, four,
three, two, one.
[panel beeps]
- The air is free
of contaminants.
- Let's go before they get
in here and recontaminate.
♪ ♪
Kimi, get us out of here.
[panel chimes]
- It's safe for everyone
to take off their helmets.
- Is everyone OK?
- Yeah.
- Good.
First order of business
when we get to "Ark 1,"
figure out how
to help those people
before they kill each other.
[ominous music]
[faint beeping]
- It's OK.
I'm fine.
- Yeah, I'll be
the judge of that.
Pupil dilation, normal.
Autonomic responses are good.
And you have no residual pain?
- I don't even have a headache.
- Seriously?
You were screaming when
that thing electrocuted you.
- Has the object been dormant
since it attacked Kelly?
- Yeah.
- But only after half of it
changed to English.
- That would explain
the results I got
from a diagnostic I ran
on Kelly's implants.
It looks like
your brain's CPU
sent out a massive data signal
when you were shocked.
I wonder if somehow
your augmentations connected
to the slab and triggered
a reverse subcarrier wave.
- I love you, but sometimes
I don't understand the words
that come out of your mouth.
- I think the slab
learned English from Kelly
through her implants.
Like it copied a whole language
from her brain.
- So it's just lucky
we have a post-human
that can connect with
the technology in this lab?
- Or the people from the cave
discovered your implants
when you were their prisoner.
- Wait, does that mean
that the triangle device
that activated the slab was
left specifically for Kelly?
- So you think I was targeted?
- Or chosen.
[tense music]
♪ ♪
[indistinct chatter]
- Thank you for helping
prove my innocence, Zed.
- We stand together
or we fall alone.
I gave Lati work release
in exchange for her aid,
but she's worried
about retribution.
- I don't blame her.
We don't know who among us
is Black Thorn
and still loyal to Ves.
- Including some people
working in security.
- Anyone on "Ark 11"
is a suspect.
- Just because they aren't
from "Ark 11"
doesn't preclude them
from being part
of another Black Thorn unit.
- So what are you saying?
We can't trust any
former GSA members
of the security team?
- What I'm saying is
we don't know if we can.
Which is why I'd like to
put a former EF security man
in charge.
- Agreed.
On an interim basis until
we round up Ves and her team.
[WD beeps]
- Trust to Felix.
I'm studying this
object you found
and, well, it'll be
easier to explain
if you just come
back out here.
- Divide and conquer?
[birds singing]
- Well, this is quite
the puzzle
you've discovered here, Felix.
Look at the scorching.
Look how the ground
is disturbed.
This is an impact radius.
- It fell from the sky?
- I think this fell from orbit.
This appears to be part
of a piece of machinery
that fused under
the heat of reentry.
- It's debris.
From what?
- Too damaged to tell.
All I do know is
that it's not ours.
- It's not from
something in orbit?
EF2 or one of those
fore-section bulbs?
- No, they're all intact.
I checked.
This has been here for
at least a year, maybe more.
- How can you be sure?
- Well, the trees are scorched,
but we're still in the shade.
This has been here long enough
for the canopy to regrow.
- That explains why
we never saw it in flyovers.
- Mr. Trust, we found
more debris to the east.
Like, a lot more.
[tense music]
♪ ♪
- Ladies and gentlemen,
let me introduce to you
Mr. Raymond Quinn.
With the unfortunate death
of Mr. Petrovic,
Mr. Quinn will be taking
command of security for now.
- He picks an EF guy.
Big surprise.
- Erica, is it?
- Yes, sir.
- I appointed
a man I served with
because I know I can trust him.
- Of course, sir.
- Does anyone else
have an opinion?
Dismissed.
There are still unidentified
Black Thorn members.
Some of them could
be among your men.
- So why don't we just relieve
all the former GSA of duty?
- Because it's easier to
catch a rat inside your house
rather than out.
[suspenseful music]
♪ ♪
[dramatic music]
[metallic clanking]
- We can't help "Ark 16"
until we figure out
what that contaminant is
and where it came from.
- Well, if they were scouting
the planet to settle,
the pre-colonization team could
have picked it up down there.
[door opens]
- Sorry I'm late.
I've been analyzing the
air sample you brought back.
- What's the verdict?
- Not good.
The particulate replicates
at an extremely high rate.
The rash you described
in the "Ark 16" crew
is likely a histamine reaction.
- So it's a virus.
- No, it's not viral.
It's also not
bacterial or parasitic.
It--it behaves in ways
I don't understand.
- Can you stop it?
- Not until I run more tests
and figure out
exactly what it is.
- We don't have time to wait.
The "Ark 16" crew is
at each other's throats.
- Some of them have
already killed each other.
Can we sedate them until
Doc Kabir figures out a cure?
- Not remotely.
- I could take a squad over,
put a sedative
into their system.
- Good idea.
Keep the team small.
Make sure you're armed.
- I'll work on
an insertion plan.
[soft suspenseful music]
♪ ♪
- Once we get to your planet,
you're going to do
as you're told.
- [grunts] Or what?
It's not like you can
actually do anything to me,
as far as I can see.
Other than give me a migraine.
That being said, it's a
pretty big friggin' migraine,
the way you just go on and on.
[door thuds]
What?
Sorry.
Baby, sorry, I was
lost in thought there.
- I left my data pad here.
- Hey, wait, wait, wait, wait.
You mad at me?
- I was attacked on a mission
and you didn't even meet me
at the airlock.
- [sighs]
I'm sorry.
Baby, I'm sorry.
I got distracted. I'm an ass.
- You've been acting strange,
and now I know why.
- Well--[scoffs]
Yeah, because I--I died.
- Don't use that as an excuse.
This started when
you left Homebase.
- What started?
- Cheating on me.
- Cheating on you? What--
what are you talking about?
- With Kimi.
- Are you being
serious right now?
- Yes.
- Do you not remember
a few months ago
when she literally
wanted me dead?
- She wanted you dead because
she was in love with you.
- What?
[laughing] Oh, my God.
- Don't make fun of me!
[ominous music]
- What the hell is that?
- Nothing.
And it's certainly none
of your damn business.
♪ ♪
- [scoffs]
- Wow.
♪ ♪
[keyboard clacking]
[monitor beeps]
[knock at door]
[door clacks]
- You got a minute?
- Yeah, I'm just waiting
for Kimi's insertion plan
for "Ark 16."
- Listen, sorry if
I was a little pushy
about coming on the mission.
Oh, and for being charming
in public.
I promise to maintain
professional propriety.
Although some of that is on you
resisting this handsome face.
- I knew it.
You don't actually
want to be with me.
- Wait.
That's not at all what I meant.
- I know what you meant.
OK?
You don't have any
real feelings for me.
- I'm confused.
Where's this coming from?
- No one can ever love me.
I'm a Gen-3 freak.
- I don't think that at all.
No one thinks that.
[suspenseful music]
♪ ♪
- The real question is...
why are you pretending
to be in love with me?
- Can we rewind for a second?
I just came by with a gift.
♪ ♪
- Pull that weapon,
and I'll snap your neck.
- I brought you
a cookie from Mess.
[breathing heavily]
♪ ♪
It's peanut butter chocolate
ch--
chip.
- You think I'm an idiot?
I know it's poisoned.
[grunts]
- [groans softly]
OK.
I think we need
to go see Dr. Kabir.
- You're not going anywhere.
♪ ♪
[keyboard clacking]
- [sighs]
[tense music]
♪ ♪
- Hey!
What were you doing in
the server room, Novak?
- Maintenance.
Why?
[groans]
What the hell, Kimi?
That hurt.
- You're an EF spy.
♪ ♪
- I don't want to fight you.
- Oh, it's not
gonna be a fight.
- The test results
for the "Ark 16" air samples.
- Oh, great.
Thank you.
Huh, interesting.
It's behaving more
like a protozoan.
We were looking at it wrong.
The infection isn't caused
by an airborne pathogen.
It's caused by
an airborne spore.
- Like a fungus.
- So it settles on the skin
and releases an ergot alkaloid
that must affect dopamine
and cortisol levels.
The rash isn't the byproduct
of the infection.
It's the cause.
Kabir to Garnet.
I have to find her.
[tense music]
♪ ♪
[dramatic music]
- Clear the way!
- [gasps]
Kimi, what is going on?
- We have to get
this spy to the brig.
♪ ♪
- The infection is on "Ark 1."
[birds singing]
[keyboard clacking]
- I drew this and this
and this and this
and this and this.
- Why?
- I have no idea,
because I drew them
all in my sleep.
I took a nap,
and I woke up on the floor,
surrounded by pages
of whatever this is.
- You did all of this
in your sleep?
- Yeah.
- This sounds like
automatic writing.
But there's no scientific proof
such a thing really exists.
- I would say it really exists.
[beeping]
- Your implants seem
to be functioning properly.
- There's nothing
wrong with them?
- Well, I didn't say that.
This lab obviously did
something to you.
We just can't detect it.
[suspenseful music]
♪ ♪
[radar beeping]
- I'm detecting more debris.
- Why haven't we found
any of this before now?
- Because we never knew
to scan for it.
- And the tree canopy's
too thick
to get a visual
from this height.
♪ ♪
[three beeps]
- It's all on one line.
- Which means it must have
been one large object
which broke apart in the upper
atmosphere leaving this trail.
- What is it?
[three beeps]
♪ ♪
[two beeps]
- Uh-huh.
- What?
- Trail stops here.
So it's possible that
whatever it was,
the bulk of it lies
at the bottom of this lake.
- I'll take us lower.
- And I'll run LiDAR scans.
If there is
something down there,
I might be able
to assemble an image.
♪ ♪
- I don't see it on here.
- Me neither.
- Well, stylistically,
they're similar.
- Very similar.
- What's similar?
- We're not seeing a match
for what you drew here.
But it's the same
as the symbol--
- I don't understand.
- We're pretty sure that
the symbols on here represent
the language of the people
who abducted you and Angus.
- No, I mean, what symbols?
That thing is all in English.
- Half of this is English.
- All of it is English.
[suspenseful music]
♪ ♪
- Are you saying
you can read this?
- Of course.
It says the same thing
on both sides.
Or almost the same.
♪ ♪
Is this a joke?
I'm not good with jokes.
- Kelly, half of this
is still just symbols.
- You really see
the same thing on both sides?
- It's not word-for-word.
It's--look here.
This says error,
but over here it says mistake.
- You're pointing
to another language.
- I swear, I--
I see it in English.
- That's so weird.
- It wasn't
a reverse subcarrier wave.
[laughs] It was
a two-way subcarrier wave!
- Wait, what?
- Huh?
- When the slab
took English from you,
it also gave you its language,
like the CPU in your brain
is translating for you.
- Gave its language.
OK, wait.
Uh, OK, if you can understand
their language,
we might finally be able to
communicate with our neighbors.
- [chuckles]
- But if I can
translate all this...
why can't I translate that?
[suspenseful music]
♪ ♪
- There is indeed
something in that lake.
- You produced an image?
- Yes.
[device thrumming]
It's a ship.
[device whirring]
[soft suspenseful music]
- It's "EF1."
- Oh, my God.
Are you sure?
♪ ♪
- [sighs]
My son's on that ship.
♪ ♪
- You stole my food rations!
- We don't have
rations anymore!
[thumping and snarling]
[tense music]
- The "Ark 16" infection
is on our--
- He's not Ian.
He's another J6-82 clone
working for Drake,
and I just need
to make him confess.
- Help me, Dr. Kabir!
She's trying to steal
my organs!
- Sharon. Sharon.
I need you to come
with me to med bay.
OK?
[tense music]
- Why?
♪ ♪
- Because you were right.
Drake is after you.
He's after me, too, because I
have Dr. Hall's Gen-3 research.
- We're in this
together, Sanji.
- Yeah.
- First, let me take care
of Drake's agent.
- No! No.
We--we--we might need
to interrogate him later.
♪ ♪
- You're the only one
I can trust, Sanji.
- [grunting]
- You coming?
- [muffled yelling]
Let me up!
[faint beeping]
- OK.
This spore synthesizes
chitin polysaccharide.
At its base, it behaves
a lot like an Earth fungus.
- Are you talking about
the "Ark 16" infection?
- Yeah, but it's
on "Ark 1" now too.
So theoretically,
a strong antifungal
will counteract it immediately.
[tense music]
- Wait.
If it's on "Ark 1,"
why don't you have it?
- Um, because I was late
to the briefing by an hour.
And that's where I would have
first been affected.
- I probably have
less than 15 minutes
until I start
exhibiting symptoms, so--
- Wow.
I'm really glad
you figured this out
before I started
showing symptoms.
- Yeah.
Me too.
[injector clicks]
- Did you just infect me
with the sickness?
- No, no, no, no,
it's the antifungal.
It's the antifungal, which, um,
apparently doesn't work.
♪ ♪
So what kills a fungus?
Damn it, this isn't
my area of expertise.
- Sounds like an Angus thing.
Shame you can't
ask him for help.
- Wait, that is a great idea.
Wait, why can't we ask
Angus for help?
- He knows what he did.
♪ ♪
Did you hear that?
- No.
- Shh!
[tense music]
[WD beeps]
- [groans]
- You never died.
It was all a lie
to cover up your affair.
- You need to defuse
this situation.
- You've lost your bloody mind.
- How is that defusing?
- Least you can do
is be honest with me.
You're in love with Kimi!
- In love with her?
She's--
[sighs]
Sweetheart, I don't know how
to pronounce the woman's name.
- Just tell me the truth.
- The truth?
- Yes!
- Fine. OK.
You want the truth?
Here's the truth.
I'm dead.
Right?
And none of this is real.
- Oh, just be a man
and come clean!
- You need to get
to the med bay.
- You faked your death
so you could be with Kimi!
- Look at the rash--
- Stop it! Stop it!
You're not real.
And you're not real.
OK.
[thud]
- I'm done with you
and your lies!
- Eva to Kimi.
Where are you?
[tense music]
♪ ♪
- Uh, have you tried
antifungal?
- OK, that was
the first thing I tried.
You think I'm a moron,
don't you?
OK. Sorry.
I don't have a lot of time.
[ominous music]
OK, actually,
I don't have any time,
so I need something right now.
- Uh, OK.
Intense UV light
could kill a fungus,
but that'll hurt.
- OK, thanks.
Bye.
♪ ♪
[UV light whirring]
[softly] OK.
♪ ♪
[sizzling]
[screams]
[groans]
♪ ♪
[door opens]
I can work with this.
- I heard a scream.
- I'm all right.
Now...
[UV light whirring]
[sighs]
We need to make sure Drake
isn't putting a tracker on you.
[suspenseful music]
[Sharon screams]
[sizzling]
That was intense.
It felt like everyone
was out to get me.
- How are you feeling now?
- [sighs] Embarrassed.
What did you do?
- UV disinfectant wand.
I turned off the safeties
and cranked it up,
but it's only
a temporary solve.
- 'Cause we don't have time
to use it on the whole crew?
- Well, and the spores are
still in the air.
- So we're already reinfected.
- Probably.
But I have an idea.
There's a small amount of UV
in our lighting system.
Yeah, to combat depression
from lack of sunlight.
- [chuckles softly]
You want to turn "Ark 1" into
a giant disinfectant wand.
- Yeah. If we can figure out
how to recalibrate
the environmental system?
[soft dramatic music]
- Well, I do happen to have an
engineer tied up in my cabin.
[soft dramatic music]
- It's only gonna hurt
a minute, I promise.
But I have to kill
the infection
that's making you sick!
- [groans]
- Almost there, almost there!
All done.
- Space virus?
Really?
- Space fungus.
- Same difference.
- Uh, big difference.
A fungus we can kill by
adjusting the UV in our lights
to disinfectant levels.
- Assuming you know
how to do that.
- Just get me
to the server room.
I'll crank it up
as high as it goes.
- Uh, it's more
complicated than that.
- If you push the UV wavelength
above 222 nanometers,
you will blind the entire ship.
- Ah.
So no pressure then.
[suspenseful music]
[Johann Strauss II's
"The Blue Danube"]
[flowing orchestral waltz]
♪ ♪
[snarling and grunting]
- You're still spying
for the EF!
- You just want
Brice for yourself!
- [gasps]
Oh, god. They're everywhere.
- They're gonna kill
each other.
- We've got this.
♪ ♪
- Stop!
- I'm gonna end
this right now!
[dramatic music]
♪ ♪
- Oh, I'm in
the environmental systems.
Turning off safeties.
♪ ♪
- [yelps]
Uh, shift our output to Far-UVC
and adjust the wavelength.
- 222 nanometers?
- That's the magic number.
- Captain!
She's an EF spy!
- She's sleeping with Brice!
- She's an EF spy!
[dramatic music]
[thuds]
- [shouts]
- Come on, come on.
We're gonna have to go dark
for this to activate.
- Do it!
♪ ♪
No, no, I thought
that would work.
Where--
[all groaning, screaming]
- Yes!
- Oh, my god.
It's working!
[sizzling and screaming]
[dramatic music]
♪ ♪
[electricity thumps]
[peaceful music]
♪ ♪
[crew groaning and coughing]
- Is everyone all right?
- They're fine.
- [sighs]
- Eva.
Uh, I'm so--
- So sorry.
- Are you guys good?
[both sigh]
[indistinct chatter]
♪ ♪
- Are you OK?
Come on.
♪ ♪
- I don't have the words
to thank you, Captain.
- Thank my crew.
They were the ones that
were able to remotely access
your environmental controls
and sterilize your ship.
- We lost 39 souls.
They were good people.
- I have no doubt.
What exactly happened?
- We followed protocol and sent
the scout team to the planet.
They came back
at each other's throats.
- Well, we'll put a beacon
into orbit to warn others
that Deno-197 isn't habitable.
- Thank you.
Where do we go now?
After years in space,
we are still homeless.
- [chuckles] Not quite.
Are you familiar
with the Trappist system?
- No.
- Well, we built a nice colony
there called Homebase 1.
[both chuckle]
♪ ♪
[metallic clanking]
[door clicks]
- [clears throat]
- [sighs]
I am so sorry.
- Stop it.
It was the fungus.
Or the spore or whatever it is
we've decided to call
that space shite.
[both chuckle]
Should we reset?
- Yes, please.
- OK.
[sighs]
- I know
there's no other woman.
- Of course there's not.
[eerie music]
♪ ♪
[indistinct chatter]
- [clears throat]
Permission to join, Captain?
- [laughs]
- Sorry.
Couldn't resist.
- Oh, please don't
make this harder.
I--I didn't mean what I said.
- Stop.
It was just the infection,
all right?
I got a little crazy too.
It's fine.
Can I let you into
a little secret?
Sometimes I get nightmares
about the fact that
I was bred for parts.
- I didn't know that.
- Because I never told you.
And anyway, you kind of
got me worried that you--
- That I'm gonna
steal your liver?
- No, that
the infection might have tapped
into your deepest fears too.
Do you really believe that
no one could ever love you?
- Of course not.
- I mean, you're way too smart
to be that dumb anyway.
Seriously.
Look.
Everyone on this ship
loves you.
Everyone.
Everyone on Homebase loves you.
And I love you.
[soft dramatic music]
I probably should have waited
till we were alone
for that last part.
- I love you too.
[tender music]
[laughter]
♪ ♪
- [chuckling] OK, Captain!
[scattered laughter]
- OK.
- [laughs]
- [mouthing words]
[laughter]
- All right.
Yes, I get it.
I understand now.
- [giggles]
- Hands are sweatin'.
[chuckles]
[sighs]
[suspenseful music]
[birds singing]
♪ ♪
- Zed?
I don't have the words.
- Then don't try.
- I've analyzed the images,
but I can't tell why
"EF1" fell out of the sky.
- I don't know
about your GSA Arks,
but Eastern Federation ships
don't generally
fall out of the sky.
- No, no, of course not.
- It must have been shot down.
- By what?
[approaching footsteps]
- You all need to see this.
It's, um--
It's bad.
[suspenseful music]
♪ ♪
We started a grid search
at the lake shore
and found an area
of disturbed ground.
So we started digging.
- What have you found?
- Bodies.
[indistinct chatter]
[tense somber music]
♪ ♪
- There were survivors.
[somber music]
♪ ♪